### Aleksei Grigorev

EU, UK · +385 99 2022511 · hello@agrigorev.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/a-grigorev/

#### **SUMMARY**

Product Design Manager and Design Expert with 12 years of UX/UI (iOS, Android, Web) experience in various business domains: FinTech, Classifieds, Travel, Corporate Software, and Digital Media. Successfully led design teams, controlled design quality, and processes at top tech companies. Designed and executed user-centered product strategies for major projects aimed at acquiring new customers. Effectively mentored and developed designers of all professional levels. Focused on the design thinking process and human-centered design principles.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Art Director (Senior Product Design Manager)**

Jul 2022 - present

Alfa Bank / Moscow, Russia

The largest private bank in Russia with 6.3 mln active digital clients

- Conceptualized, designed, and executed the product design strategy for integrating banking services into VK Messenger (56.3 million active users), resulting in +275,000 new active users per month
- Designed and executed a user-centered product strategy for the Alfa Bank mobile application for kids, resulting in over 300,000 new parents as customers
- Successfully led a major redesign of Alfa Bank's mobile app, which reduced the completion time of key tasks by 20%

# **Product Design Manager**

2020 - 2022

Yandex LLC / Moscow, Russia

*Top tech company in Europe*  $\approx 21~000$  *employees* 

- Organized and successfully implemented a user research process at Auto.ru (product DAU 4 mln)
- Designed and integrated a competency map for product designers of all levels at Auto.ru, which made the process of designers' growth transparent
- Conceptualized and executed a cutting-edge 360-degree panorama design for listings, resulting in a 40% increase in engagement and viewing of car cards (selling time reduced by 12%)

# **Principal Product Designer (Lead Product Designer)**

2017 - 2020

Yandex LLC / Moscow, Russia

*Top tech company in Europe*  $\approx 21~000$  *employees* 

- Conceptualized and designed the offer posting form, reducing the time required for completion from 30 to 15 minutes
- Elevated brand recognition and boosted website traffic by designing Mag.Auto.ru, Russia's premier digital media about cars
- Revolutionized the listing UX/UI, leading to a reduced response time by 15% and an increase in loan applications by 8%

### **EDUCATION**

- British Higher School of Art and Design Interactive Design and New Media / Moscow, Russia, 2014
- Moscow State Institute of Radio Engineering, Electronics and Automation Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering / Moscow, Russia, 2011

#### **SKILLS**

Product Design, Art Direction, Design Leadership, User-Centered Design, Design Strategy, Cross-Functional Collaboration, Design Management, UX/UI Expertise, Creative Direction, Design Thinking, Team Management, Product Innovation, Design Operations, Design Vision, Mentorship, Stakeholder Management, Mobile Application Design, iOS/Android Guidelines, Startup Launch, Web Design, User Research.